这真是世上最美的订婚戒指
God, that is the most beautiful engagement ring ever!
你一定了解啦  你买过一大堆
Yeah, well. You should know. You bought, like, a billion of them.
但是没给你买过啊
Yeah, you didn't get one.
好  就是今晚了
Okay. Well, tonight's the big night.
你要怎么求婚
Listen. How you gonna ask her?
我会弄得很完美
It is going to be perfect.
带她去她最爱的餐厅
I am taking her to her favorite restaurant.
还要点一瓶她最喜欢的香槟
l'm gonna get her a bottle of champagne that she really love.
这样她知道那有多贵
Therefore knows how expensive it is.
然后等酒斟好了
Then when the glasses are full,
我不会  敬酒  我会向她求婚
instead of proposing a toast, l'm gonna propose.
好棒喔
lt sounds perfect!
你会搞砸  让我来吧
You’re gonna mess it up let me do it.
我才不会搞砸
I'm not gonna mess it up.
要是她说不  戒指可以给我吗
lf she says no, can l have the ring?
她不会说不
She's not gonna say no.
要是
If.
莫妮卡
Hey, Monica.
-还给我  -吞下去了
- Give it. - lt's gone.
菲比
Phoebe.
莫妮卡
Hey, Monica!
我们这样也算是在接吻喔
We're practically kissing.
晚上有人有空吗
Are any of you guys free tonight?
我主管要主持救助贫童慈善会
My boss is hosting this charity event for underprivileged kids
我带越多人去越有面子
and the more people I bring,
莫妮卡  钱德勒  要来吗
the better l look. So, Monica? Chandler?
莫妮卡和钱德勒不能去  订了晚饭
Well, Monica and Chandler can't go. We're going to dinner.
记得吗
Remember?
-天哪  真抱歉  -又不是什么大事
- Oh, my God. l'm so sorry. - What's the big deal?
我只是很气瑞秋不记得  我们要去哪里
I just get mad when Rachel doesn't remember where we're going.
你们要去哪里
Where are you going?
-那你们呢   -酒品免费吗
- How about you guys? - Open bar?
-应该是  -我可以为孩子们喝酒
- l think so. - l can do that for the kids.
那我也要去
Hey, y'know what? I'll come too.
我有收入了  要回馈社会
I'm making money now; it's about time I give something back.
你也可以把欠我的钱还给我
You could give back the money you owe me.
好啊  你办义卖啊
Okay. Have a benefit.
罗斯  你晚上可以参加慈善晚会吗
Hey! Ross, listen can you come to a charity event tonight?
不行  我跟伊丽莎白有约
Oh no, I have plans with Elizabeth.
你已经在为孩童贡献心力了
Oh, so you're already doing your part for the kids.
抱歉  我们要珍惜今晚
I'm sorry, it's just one of our last nights together
过几天她要去夏令营了
before she leaves for camp
是去当指导员
to be a counselor.
罗斯  我问你  撇开笑话不提
Ross let me ask you a question. All jokes aside,
这段感情要往哪里走
where is this relationship going?
等等  撇开笑话不提  我可不同意
Wait a minute, all jokes aside? l didn't agree to that.
-你认为你们可以长久吗  -我不知道
- Do you see this as long-term thing? - l don't know.
你比她大十二岁喔
You know, you are 12 years older than her.
等等  你们都这么认为吗
Wait a minute, does-does everyone feel this way?
-有一点  -抱歉
- Yeah, sort of. - Sorry.
我以为你们只是爱开玩笑  我没想到
l thought you were just making jokes. l had no idea.
不过你们都错了
But you know what? You guys are wrong.
没错  我们是有年龄上的差异
Yes, there is a chronological age difference.
但是我都感觉不到  因为她很成熟
But l never notice it, you know what? Because she is very mature.
况且我根本不在意你们的看法
Besides, it doesn't really matter to me what you guys think.
跟她交往的是我  不是你们
I mean, I'm the one dating Elizabeth, not you!
她昨晚可不是这么说的
That's not what she said last night.
他配她就够幼稚
See, now, he could date her.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
喂  快嫁给我
Hey, you marry me.
怎么啦  小精灵们
What's going on, little elves?
今晚很重要  我们想祝你好运
lt's the big night.We wanted to wish you good luck!
-戒指带了吗  -就在口袋里
- Yeah, yeah you have the ring? - Yeah, right here in my pocket.
-菲比  -什么
- Pheebs. - Wha...?
麻烦你们出去
Okay, now will you guys get out of here?
我想给她惊喜  你们在这会露馅的
I want this is to be a surprise and she's gonna know.
没错  你们快出去
Yeah, you guys. Get out of here.
你们好
Hey, guys.
-你好漂亮  -谢谢
- You look beautiful. - Thank you.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们只是...
We're just really...
要参加慈善晚会觉得很兴奋
...excited about this charity event we have to go to.
-给你  -谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
-现在是怎样  -这是一场缄默拍卖会
- So now what's going on here? - Well, this is a silent auction.
要卖的东西都在这里  你写下竞标价
They lay out all the stuff here and then you write down your offer
出价最高的就是得主
And then the highest bid gets it.
我知道什么叫缄默拍卖
l know what a silent auction is.
我是说你的头发怎么了
I meant, what's going on with your hair?
-怎么说  -不是啊  很好看
- Why? - No, it's nice.
瑞秋  欢迎  你带了一位朋友来
Nice to see you Rachel. So glad you brought someone.
一位  我带了一群呢
Someone? l brought people.
汤普森先生  这位是菲比
Mr. Thompson, this is Phoebe.
菲比  这位是汤普森先生
Phoebe, this is Mr.Thompson.
他是我的部门主管
He's the head of my department.
-我还带了我的朋友乔伊  -虾子吐司
- And l also brought my friend Joey. - Shrimp toast!
我不知道他在哪里
You know, l don't know where he is.
希望你会参加竞标
Well, I hope you're gonna bid on some things Rachel.
其实
Well, you know what? Actually,
我正打算投标这趟巴黎之旅
I was about to bid on this lovely trip to Paris.
-有眼光  祝你好运  -谢谢
- Nice choice. Good luck. - Thank you.
好
Okay.
二十元
Twenty dollars.
把门关上  把门关上
Shut the door! Shut the door!
怎么了
What's going on?
对面的男生在朝我们丢水球
The guys across the hall are throwing water balloons at us.
你们得报警
Oh, you have to call the police!
我都这样对付我家那栋的小孩
That's what I did to the kids in my building!
这是水球仗  是我们挑起的
No, it's a water balloon fight. We started it.
听我说  我来问你
Listen, l just stopped by
晚上要不要去看戏
to see if you wanted to see this play tonight.
这出戏应该很棒  导演...
it's supposed to be excellent. The director is...
谁把神风特攻队都喝了
Who drank all the kamikazes?
没有  在水球里
Nobody. We put them in here!
你要吗  不要
You want some?
好了  好了
Ok, ok.
-我可以跟你讲一下话吗   -当然可以
- Could l talk to you for a second? - Yeah, sure.
所以你要去看戏吗
So this play, what do you think?
-它的剧评很好  -攻击!
- lt's gotten great reviews... - Attack!
-放下水球  你们才放下  -你们才放下
- Put your balloons down! - You put your balloons down!
统统都把水球放下
Everybody put their balloons down!
这可是高级西装
Now, this is a nice suit!
下一项拍卖品是巴黎浪漫之旅
Our next item is the romantic trip to Paris.
艾弥尔·亚历山大  以两千三百元得标
lt goes to Emil Alexander with a high bid of $2300.
只差一点
So close!
你们看  我拿了几杯酒
Guys, look. Got me some drinks.
-你在干什么  -不用钱嘛
- What are you doing? - Open bar.
最后是今晚的最大项目
And finally, our biggest item tonight.
二十二英尺豪华帆船
The 22-foot Gentleman's Daysailer sailboat.
得标金额高达两万元
The winning bid was a whopping $20,000.
我赢了
l won.
那是我猜的
That was my guess.
-什么  -我猜两万
- What? What? What? - l guessed $20,000.
乔伊  这是拍卖会  不是猜  是买
Joey, it is an auction. You don't guess. You buy!
什么
What?
我没有两万
l don't have $20,000.
恭喜你购得新船...  乔伊·崔比安尼
Congratulations on your new boat, Joey Tribbiani.
坐下啦
Joey, sit down.
别理她  开心就好
Forget her. You enjoy this.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
"一个国家
''One nation...
在神之下  不可分割  全民拥有  自由公正"
...under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all. ''
我记得是这样背  香槟来了
l remembered it. The champagne is here.
-你没事吧  -我很好  你好吗
- You okay? - Yes. Yes. l'm good. Are you good? Are you good?
这一切...你很好吗
ls everything...? Are you perfect?
还好
Yeah. l'm okay.
-其实我有点冷  外套可以借我吗  -可以
- Actually, l'm a bit cold. Can l have your jacket? - Oh, yeah.
不行  我的外套不能借你
No, you can't have my jacket.
因为那样我就会冷
Because then l would be cold.
你要是觉得会冷
lf you thought you'd be cold,
应该自己带外套
you should've brought your own jacket.
除此之外你好吗
But, other than that, are you okay? are you okay?
-你真的没事吗  -对  我很好
- Are you sure you're okay? - Yes. l'm fine.
我这段日子一直都很好  我觉得...
ln fact, l've been fine for a long time now and l think...
都是拜你所赐
...the reason is you.
好甜蜜喔
That's sweet.
好了
Okay.
认识你之前  我的人生微不足道
Before l met you, l had really little life.
-我无法想像一个人  -我的天哪
- And l couldn't imagine growing old... - Oh, my God.
我知道  不过让我说完
l know. But let me say it.
我的天哪  理查德
Oh my god, Richard.
什么   我是钱德勒
What? l'm Chandler.
那是理查德
Oh, that's Richard.
天哪  也许他会没看见  理查德
Oh god. Maybe he won't see us. Richard!
莫妮卡  钱德勒
Monica. Chandler.
我不知道我为什么要抱你
l don't know why l did that.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
彼此彼此  你把头发留长了
You too. You let your hair grow long.
没错  你一直希望我留长
Yeah, oh, that's right. You always wanted me to.
你又开始留胡子了
l see your mustache is back.
我的鼻子感到寂寞嘛
Well, my nose got lonely.
你没留胡子  很好
And you don't have a mustache, which is good.
我是钱德勒  我一蹩扭就开玩笑
I'm Chandler. l make jokes when l'm uncomfortable.
抱歉  丽莎  莫妮卡  钱德勒  我们交往过
l'm sorry. Lisa, Monica, Chandler. We used to date.
理查德  我们的事应该保密的
Richard, no one's supposed to know about us.
我又来了
See? l did it again.
-钱德勒  我们坐下吧  -好  我坐
- Chandler, what if we sit down. - Yeah l'll sit down.
-很高兴见到你  -您的桌子准备好了
- It's good to see you. - Your table's ready, sir.
-很高兴遇见你们  -好
- Good to see you guys. - Yes.
这一桌也是空的
Or if you prefer, this table's available.
一起坐应该不错
That might be fun.
-你在想什么啊  -我不知道这是拍卖会
- What were you thinking? - l didn't know it was an auction.
我以为猜一猜
l figured l'd take a guess.
帮助慈善团体  免费得帆船
Help a charity. Free boat!
慈善团体为什么要送帆船
Why would a charity give away a free boat?
我哪知  做慈善吗
l don't know. Charity?
你就买吧
Well, just buy the damn boat.
菲比  你喝得够多了吧
Phoebe, don't you think you've had enough to drink?
我只是在帮助儿童
l'm just helping the kids.
你喝酒怎么能帮助儿童
How is you drinking helping the kids?
我喝得越多
Because the more l drink,
孩子们能喝的就越少
the less there is for the kids to drink.
崔比安尼先生  你的慷慨解囊
Mr. Tribbiani, your generous contribution brings us
让兴建活动中心的事大有进展
a big step closer to building the youth center.
我很好奇  那艘船原价多少
Just out of curiosity, how-how much is that boat worth?
差不多是一万九
l think it was valued at 19,000.
我猜得蛮准的
Hey, l was pretty close.
坏消息
So, bad news.
我不能买那艘船  我没有钱
l can't buy the boat. l don't have any money.
乔伊  你真幽默
Joey! Joey, good one. He's silly.
你真会演
Good! Very good!
好吧  我要闪人了
So uh listen, I think I'm gonna take off now.
你不能走  乔伊
You can't leave, Joey!
你同意要买船  具有约束力
You agreed to buy that boat, all right?! lt's a contract.
而且你走了  我的主管会宰了我
And plus if you leave, my boss will kill me.
那怎么办   我没有那么多钱
Well, what am I gonna do Rach?! I don't have that kind of money!
我知道  好  这样吧
l know. Okay, okay. All right. All right, this is what we'll do.
我们去找出价第二高的人
we are gonna go to the next highest bidder,
然后让他们去买
and we are just gonna let them buy it,
你只要付差价
and then you'll pay the difference.
好吧  我真不明白
Okay. Look l don't know why the kids
这些小孩要活动中心干嘛啊
need a youth center anyway.Y'know?
放了学跟我一样看电视就好啦
They should just watch TV after school like l did.
我现在也蛮好的啊
l turned out fine.
但是不够优秀
Not great.
我们躲在洗手间里
So we're hiding in the bathroom....
然后我溜出来  但莫妮卡还没出来
And-and then I sneak out and before Monica can,
她父母就进去了
her parents come in.
于是我躲到浴帘后面
l hide in the shower and the next thing you know
接着他们就在地上做起来了
they're going at it right on the bathroom floor.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我有一个  我有一个
I got a good one, I got a good one!
我有一次撞见我父母  跟同一个男人做爱
l once walked in on both my parents making love to the same guy.
遇见你们真的好开心  我想敬酒
lt's so great seeing you guys again. l'd like to make a toast.
一位诗人说过  "在友谊的甜蜜里
As a poet once said, ''ln the sweetness of friendship...
尽情欢笑  分享欢乐吧
...let there be laughter and sharing of pleasures for,
人心正是从中获得朝气
in the dew of little things,
焕然一新"
the heart finds its morning and is refreshed. ''
什么
What?
天哪  你们
Oh, my God! You guys!
在你开口之前  我们有事要说
Before you say anything, we got a story for you!
你猜我们吃饭时遇见谁
Guess who we bumped into at dinner?
-谁  -理查德  什么
- Who? - Richard!
你不是要跟伊丽莎白约会
I thought you were going out with Elizabeth.
没错  但是她忙着打水球仗
Yeah, I was but uh, she was a little busy with a water balloon fight.
有时"大人"就是
Oh Ross, sometimes grown-ups have commitments
会有事无法脱身
they just can't get out of!
也许她真的太年轻了
Maybe she is too young for me.
当我看到她跟朋友横冲直撞
When l was over there, and she was running around with her friends,
我觉得我好像保姆
l felt like l was a babysitter.
我开始了解你们的话了
I finally started to see what you guys were talking about.
我该怎么办啊
l don't know what to do.
你可以比较
Why don't you just weigh out
这段感情的利与弊
the good stuff about the relationship against the bad stuff.
我当初就是这样...比较东西的
That's what l did when l first started... weighing stuff.
好  弊
Okay, bad stuff.
我比她大十二岁
Well, l'm 1 2 years older than she is.
学校发现会开除你
If the school finds out you're fired.
-她要离开三个月  -参加夏令营
- She's leaving for three months. - For camp.
好  利
Okay, good stuff.
她很甜很漂亮...
Well, she's sweet and pretty and...
罗斯  你只需要问自己
Look Ross, the only question you need to ask is,
与她有未来吗
Do you see a future?''
你能想像跟她结婚吗
I mean like, do you see yourself marrying her?
天哪  你已经娶她了对不对
Oh my God! You did it already! You married her, didn't you?!
没有啦  我只是...
No! No! I... didn't do that. It's just...
好吧  我觉得我们没什么未来
Okay, honestly, no. l don't see a big future with her.
那这就是你的答案了
Okay, well, l think that's your answer.
我得告诉她  我最恨做这事了
l gotta talk to her. l hate this part.
你必须忘记伊丽莎白  你要是不小心
Hey you have to forget about Elizabeth. lf you're not careful...
今年可能会结不到婚呢
...you may not get married at all this year.
-出价第二高的人在一号桌  -太好了
-Rach! Rachel! Next highest bidder is at table one. - Great.
标到巴黎之旅的人坐四号桌  好
Oh and the guy who got the Paris trip is at table four.
你干嘛问谁赢了巴黎之旅
Why do you care about the guy who won the Paris trip?
那是双人之旅
lt's a trip for two.
失陪
Excuse me.
抱歉  标到巴黎之旅的人  在这一桌吗
Excuse me, ils the person who won the Paris trip at this table?
-我就是  -您好
- That was me. - Enchante.
-抱歉  有没有一位波芒先生  -我就是
-Excuse me. ls there a Mr. Bowmont at this table? - That's me.
你好  你今天走运了  波芒先生
Well, hello. This is your lucky day, Mr. Bowmont.
那艘帆船又要卖了
The Gentleman Daysailer has become available again...
你开了一万八的价格
...and l believe you made a bid of $ 18,000.
你得付钱  不是猜好玩的
You have to pay that. lt's not just a guess.
其实没标到我松了口气
l was relieved l didn't win the boat.
我老婆会宰了我的
My wife would've killed me.
不会吧   她会爱死这艘船
You kidding? She'll love this boat!
-是啊  尊夫人芳名   -她叫潘
-Yeah. What is your wife's name? -It's Pam.
潘
Pam!
天哪  想像一下"潘号"
Just imagine this: The Pam.
我想她不会喜欢
l don't think she'd like that.
那想像...  "波芒先生号"
Okay. lmagine this: The Mr. Bowmont.
-还是不要了  -让我为你描绘一下
- l don't think so dear. - Let me paint you a little picture.
你在哈德逊河上航行
All right, You are setting sail up the Hudson.
风吹过你的头...臂弯
You've got the wind in your... arms.
你得到你企盼已久的安宁
You get all that peace and quiet you've always wanted.
你回到大自然怀抱  你可以钓鱼
You get back to nature. You can go fishing.
你可以买一顶帽子  让大家叫你船长
You get one of those hats. And people call you captain.
等你老了就是老船长
And then when you're old, Cappy.
管他的  不买说不过去  我买了
What the hell. lt's for a good cause. All right.
你别想  船是我的
No way! lt's mine!
什么   什么
What? What?
你刚才说的那些事我也要
All the stuff you said, l want that!
但是乔伊  你没有两万
But Joey, you don't have $20,000!
管他的  我分期也行
Who cares? l'll make payments!
我要"波芒先生号"
Whatever it takes, l want the Mr. Bowmont!
天哪  你们回来了
Oh, my God. You're back.
让我  看你的手  让我看你的手
Let me see it. Let me see your hand.
你为什么要看我的手
Why do you wanna see my hand?
我想看你手上拿的垃圾
l wanna see what's in your hand. l wanna see the trash.
好脏  你最好拿去扔
lt's all dirty. You should throw this out.
好吧
Ok.
-你们搞什么  -怎么回事
- What did you guys just do? - What happened?
-理查德也在  我无法开口  -不会吧
- Richard was there. So l couldn't do it. - Oh, no.
我要延到明天  给她惊喜
I'm gonna do it tomorrow y'know,  and-and surprise her,
-却被你们破坏了  -我们没有破坏
- But now you've ruined it. - We didn't ruin it!
谁会一进门就要看别人的手
Who walks in a room and asks to see a person's hands?
算命师  修指甲的小姐  手部医生...
A palm reader, a manicurist, a hand doctor....
-手套推销员  -漂亮
- Glove salesman. - Good one!
真惨  我该怎么办
This is terrible. What am I going to do?
她只是在怀疑  又不是确定
Look, she only suspects something okay?
错误引导她就行了
She doesn't know for sure, so just throw her off the track.
可以骗她
That's right, I can throw her off.
让她觉得我完全不考虑结婚
l'll pretend marriage is the last thing on my mind.
让她相信你很害怕承诺
Yeah! Yeah! Convince her that-that you're scared of commitment!
我做得到  我练三十年了
l can do that. l've had years of practice.
养兵千日  终于能用在一时啦
Being you is finally gonna pay off!
我刚跑去地下室扔了
I had to go all the way to the basement,
某个白痴小孩老用披萨盒把垃圾槽堵住
some idiot keeps stuffing the trash chute with pizza boxes.
那个家伙还是没改啊
That guy is still doing that?
天哪  你们回来了  我看看你的手
Oh my God you're here, let me see your hand!!
来不及了  她已经把垃圾拿去扔了
You're too late! She already took out the trash!
我从没有过这么平和的分手
l have never had such a healthy breakup.
她表现得好成熟
She was such a grownup about it.
我觉得她一点也不幼稚
She didn't seem too immature for me.
我是不是犯了个大错啊
Did l just make a huge mistake?
罗斯  等等
Ross! Wait!
伊丽莎白  太好了  我正在想说...
Elizabeth, thank God. l was just thinking about...
你最烂了
You suck!
什么
What?
好吧
Ok.
好  分手还是有效
Breakup's still on.
她来了
Okay, okay, here she comes!
我像不像不想结婚的人
How do I look? Do I look like a guy who doesn't want to get married?
像  还有点像法国人
Yeah! And also, a little like a French guy.
我第一次发现呢
l never noticed that before.
-你们在干什么  -在随便聊聊网站之类的
- What are you up to? - Hanging out. Talking about websites.
有一个网站在讨论婚姻
We saw this interesting website about marriage...
及婚姻的一无是处
...and how totally unnecessary it is,
说那只是政府监视你的方式
and how it is just a way for the government to keep tabs on you.
是啊  专制
Yeah, Big Brother.
有点夸张
That's a bit crazy.
不过你们总算上了
Although I am y'know glad to hear
其他类别的网站
that you're branching out on what you look at on the Internet.
不过我就想
Y'know, it just got me thinking though.
为什么会有人想要结婚
Why would anybody want to get married?
因为要赞颂这段感情
Why?! To celebrate your relationship!
要巩固你们的承诺
To solidify your commitment!
要向全世界宣布你们的爱
To declare your love for one another to the world.
能知道你的反应真好
Okay, well, that's good to know.
"波芒先生号"来了
The Mr. Bowmont is here!
莫妮卡  有客人想向主厨致意
Hey Monica, there's a customer who wants to compliment the chef,
让他进来吗
Shall l let him in?
当然  我最爱这种事了
Sure. l love this part.
-进来吧  -你好吗
- Come on in. - Hi.
-理查德  -其实我不是来向主厨致意的
- Richard. - Actually, I'm not here to compliment the chef.
没关系  我最讨厌客人跑来致意
Oh, that's okay I hate when people come back to compliment the chef.
好像我很闲似的
Like l have nothing better to do.
你有什么事
So, what's up?
那天晚上遇见你很开心
lt was great seeing you the other night.
我也很开心
Good to see you too.
你就是来说这个的吗
Did you come down here to tell me that?
不是  我是来说别的
No! I came here to tell you something else.
我是来说我仍然爱你
l came here to tell you l still love you.
什么  你刚才...什么
What? What did you...? What?
我仍然爱你
l still love you.
我知道我甚至不该告诉你
l know l shouldn't even be here telling you this.
你跟钱德勒在一起  我很喜欢他
I mean, you're with Chandler, who l  really like.
你说他是异性恋  我就相信你
lf you say he's straight, l'll believe you.
但那天见到你之后
After seeing you the other night,
我知道我不说会后悔一辈子
l knew if l didn't tell you l'd regret it for the rest of my life.
放弃你是我所做过最蠢的事
Letting you go was the stupidest thing l ever did.
你不该到厨房来的
You're really not supposed to be back here.
我知道  对不起
I know. l'm sorry.
我知道时机地点都不对
l know this is the wrong time and the wrong place...
但是  我一定要说
...but l had to tell you.
我想跟你共度一生  我想娶你
l wanna spend my life with you. l wanna marry you.
我想跟你生儿育女
l wanna have kids with you.
这里为什么没摆椅子
Oh, my God. Why don't they put chairs back here?
我知道这很疯狂  来不及了吗
Look, l know this is crazy, but am l too late?
没错  你三年前怎么不说这些话
Yes. You're too late. Where was all this three years ago?
我知道  我是个白痴
l know. l was an idiot.
我也想忘记你  真的
l tried to forget you. l really did.
我们去年吃完饭
You know what, after our last lunch,
我跑去非洲六个月想忘记你呢
I spent six months in Africa trying to get you out of my head!
-你去非洲做什么  -帮助盲童
- What did you do there? - Work with blind kids.
你干嘛这么折磨我
What are you doing to me?
瞧
Look, l....
很抱歉  我们之间是不可能的
l'm sorry, but this is not gonna happen.
好  我会离开
That's fine. l'll walk away.
再也不会来烦你
l'll never bother you again.
但前提是  钱德勒也愿意给你这一切
Only if you say Chandler's willing to give you everything l am.
他愿意
Well, he is. Yeah. l mean...
没错  他成天把婚姻挂在嘴边
...marriage is all he talks about. My goodness!
事实上是我在让他等
ln fact, l'm the one making him wait.
是吗  对
You are? Why?
为什么
Why?
因为政府的阴谋
Because of the government.
很棒吧
lsn't it incredible?
莫妮卡和钱德勒要结婚了
Monica and Chandler are getting married.
就是啊  他们会很幸福
l know. They'll be so happy together.
与最要好的朋友坠入爱河
I mean two best friends falling in love,
多难能可贵啊
how often does that happen?
-的确不容易  -没错
- Not that often. - No.
-我好替他们开心  -我也好开心
- l'm so happy for them. - Me too. So happy for them.
我很高兴  毫无嫉妒之心
l'm so happy and not at all jealous.
没错  当然没有
Oh, no! God, definitely not jealous.
我可能是98%开心  2%嫉妒
l'm probably 98% happy and maybe 2% jealous.
-2%等于没有  -没错
- l mean, what's 2%? That's nothing. - Totally.
-我是九比一  -我也是
- l'm like 90/10. - Yeah. Me too.
你们有见到钱德勒吗
Have you guys seen Chandler?
没有  但你知道谁来找过你吗
No, but y’know who did stop in here looking for ya,
坦妮尔[船长与坦妮尔乐团]
Tennille.
你昨天说的那些话
The marriage stuff you were saying yesterday?
应该不是真心话吧
You don't believe that. Do you?
当然是
Sure, l do.
事实上我觉得婚姻本身  就很不近人情
ln fact, l think the concept of marriage is unnatural.
你看猪嘛  我们来看一下猪
I mean, look at pigs. Let's take a second here and look at pigs.
猪不会有固定配偶
Pigs don't mate for life.
猪的一生可以有一百个性伴侣
A pig can have 100 sexual partners in a lifetime.
那还只是普通的猪
That's an ordinary pig,
还不是擅长运动的猪呢
not even a pig that's good at sports.
你是说你
Are you honestly telling me
可能永远都不想结婚吗
that-that you may never want to get married?
话不能说死  不过应该是...
Never say never, but, you know, probably...
永远不会
...yeah, never.
天哪  那我们在干什么  现在是怎样
Oh, my God. Then what are we even doing? What is this?
干嘛对我施压
Whoa, whoa, whoa! What is all this pressure?
这是某种新策略吗
ls this some new kind of strategy?
你别再搞尔虞我诈那一套了
Why don't you put down your copy of The Rules, huh, mantrap?
你知道吗   我要走了
You know what? l gotta go.
放心  我自有打算
lt's okay. l got a plan.
-我们会找到真爱的  -一定会的
- We're gonna find love. - Definitely.
我对这点有信心
Yeah, l'm pretty confident about that.
所以我可以有八成
That's what makes it so easy
替莫妮卡和钱德勒高兴
to be 80%/ happy for Monica and Chandler.
不过要是有保障就好了
It would be nice to have a little guarantee though.
什么意思
What do you mean?
有些人不是会跟朋友约定
Well y'know, some people make deals with a friend,
要是两个人到了四十都没结婚
like if neither of them are married by 40,
他们就要结婚
they marry each other.
-你是指备胎  -没错
- You mean a backup? - Exactly.
我已经找好了
Yeah, l've got that.
你找好了
You do?
-是谁  -乔伊
- Who? - Joey.
-乔伊  真的吗  -好几年前就说好了
- Joey? Are you serious? - Yeah, l locked him in years ago.
所以要是你们四十岁还没结婚
Wait. So if neither of you are married by 40,
你就要嫁给乔伊吗
you're gonna marry Joey.
对  我们握手为定了
Yep. We shook on it.
不过他可不想就此打住
But believe me, that is not how he wanted to seal the deal.
是吗
Oh, seriously?
对  他说的是...
l think his exact words were...
真迷人
Charming.
只是个备胎
He's just a backup.
-莫妮卡  -你有见到瑞秋或照镜子吗
- Hey, Monica. - Have you seen Rachel? Or a mirror?
-这是我的船长装  酷吧  -很酷
- lt's for my boat. Pretty cool, huh? - Yeah, it's great.
怎么了  告诉船长
What's wrong? Talk to the captain.
我又发现
I’m just having one of those days
这段感情是死路一条
where you realize you're in a dead-end relationship!
钱德勒欺负你是吧
Chandler giving you a hard time huh?
我又不是明天就要结婚
l don't want marriage tomorrow.
我只是想知道
It's just that I-I'd like to believe
我们有个目标
that I'm in a relationship that's actually going somewhere,
而不是在原地打转  浪费时间
that l'm not wasting time.
你也了解钱德勒
You know Chandler.
我已经不了解钱德勒了
No, l don't know Chandler.
仿佛有什么事变了
Not anymore. lt's like something's changed.
-也许是你变了  -我才没变
- Maybe you changed. - l didn't change.
也许问题就在这里
Maybe that's the problem.
-什么  -钱德勒很复杂
- What? - Chandler is a complex fellow.
不太可能娶妻
One who is unlikely to take a wife.
他是怎么想的
What does he think?
他以为我会空等下去吗
Does he think l'll wait around for nothing?
面对现实吧  钱德勒反对婚姻
Monica. Face it. Chandler is against marriage.
他是不会变了
And always will be.
有些人可是真心想娶我呢
There's some people who do wanna marry me.
-有吗  -有  理查德
- There are? - Yeah. Richard.
理查德说他想娶你
Richard said he wants to marry you?
钱德勒说他痛恨婚姻
And-and Chandler's tellin'ya how much he hates marriage?!
没错
That's right.
钱德勒热爱婚姻
Chandler loves marriage!
你刚刚才说他痛恨婚姻
You just told me that he hates marriage!
说他很复杂  不太可能娶妻
''He's a complex fellow who's unlikely to take a wife'' !
说他会永远反对婚姻
''He's against marriage and always will be'' !
你就这么解读我的话啊
You got that from what l said?
-瑞秋  -帅哥
- Rach. - Hey, you.
-请进  -谢谢
- Come on in. - Thank you.
很遗撼你跟伊丽莎白分手了
You know, l'm so sorry to hear about you and Elizabeth.
谢谢  我以为我们能克服万难  不过...
Thanks. l really thought we'd be able to make it work.
这大概是有缘无分吧
l guess it wasn't meant to be.
是啊  爱情...爱情真是微妙
Yeah. Love. lt's a tricky business, isn't it?
-是啊  -我们要不要来做个约定
- l guess so. - So, what do you say we make a pact?
要是我们到了四十都还没结婚  我们就结婚
lf you and l are both single by 40, we get married.
我们互相认识  互相喜欢
l mean, we know each other, we like each other...
我们已经上过床
...we've already slept together,
不会有惊讶的地方
so there'll be no surprises there. You know what I mean?
不会有什么"哇靠"
No, like, ''What's that?''
-你想找我当备胎  -没错
- Oh, you want me to be your backup. - Exactly.
我已经有备胎了
Yeah. l already have one.
-是谁  -菲比
- What? Who? - Phoebe.
菲比
Phoebe?
但是她说乔伊是她的备胎
But she just said Joey is her backup.
才不是呢
Oh, l don't think so.
我刚跟她聊过  她说她和乔伊约好了
Ross. We just spoke. She said that she and Joey made a deal.
不可能的  我们早就约好了
That's impossible. I mean we have had a deal for years.
还握手为定
We shook on it.
不过我可以告诉你  她想要的不只是那样呢
although believe me she wanted to do a lot more than that.
你上哪儿去了
Where the hell have you been?!
我在跟教授做椰子电话
l was making a coconut phone with the Professor.
理查德跟莫妮卡说他想娶她
Richard told Monica he wants to marry her.
-什么  -就是啊  我一直想去找你
- What? - Yeah. Yeah. l've been trying to find you.
让你别再吓唬她了
Tell you to stop messing with her.
要不是这双鞋
And l would have
跑一跑就掉  我早找着你了
if these damn boat shoes wouldn't keep flying off!
-我的天哪  -就是啊  烂死了
- Oh, my God! - l know! They suck!
他不该向我的女朋友求婚
He's not supposed to ask her to marry him!
该求婚的人是我
I'm supposed to do that!
-我知道啊  -那...
- l know! - What...?
你知道吗   我要去找他教训他
You know what l'll do? l'll go over there and kick his ass!
你愿意帮忙吗
Will you help me?
钱德勒  被他海扁一顿不是办法
Look, l don't think us getting our asses kicked is a solution, okay?
-赶快去找莫妮卡吧  -你说得对
- Look, just go and find Monica. - You're right.
好  我去拿戒指  我去拿戒指
Okay. l'm gonna get the ring...
我要找到她  直接向她求婚
...l'm gonna go find her and l'm just gonna propose!
好  老兄  怎样
Dude! Dude! Dude! - What?
之后让我看看你的椰子电话
Let me know about that coconut phone,
也许很适合摆在船上
it might be great for the boat.
我不知道我来干什么
l don't know why l'm here.
我又没问
l didn't ask.
-你要进来吗  -我不知道
- You wanna come in? - l don't know.
好吧
Oh, okay.
那我把门开着  回去坐下
Well l'll just leave the door open and sit on the couch.
-钱德勒真是个白痴  -喝酒吗
- Chandler is such an idiot! - Drink?
-好  我要威士忌加...  -冰块和莱姆片
- Yeah. Scotch on the... - Rocks with a twist?
我记得
l remember.
还在抽雪茄吗
You still smoking cigars?
不  那是艺术
No, no. That's art.
如果你不喜欢  我可以把艺术熄掉
lf it bothers you, l can put my art out.
没关系
No, that's okay.
莫妮卡  我问你一件事
So, Monica, let me ask you a question.
我们分手后
Since we broke up, do you ever...
你想过我吗
...think about me?
我两个月前还想到你
Actually, l thought about you a few months ago.
-是吗  -不过是因为
- Really? - But it's because...
我去做眼睛检查  又不喜欢新医生
...l had an eye exam, and l don't like my new eye doctor.
-是谁  -爱德华·奈夫斯基
- Who is it? - Edward Nevsky.
他的确很差
Yeah. He's no good.
你有想过我吗
Do you ever think about me...
-在非需要眼科医生的时候  -没有
- ... in a non- eye- doctor way? - No.
因为忘记你
Because getting over you was the hardest thing
是我这辈子最难的事
that I've ever had to do..
我不让自己想到你
l never let myself think about you.
菲比  你找了乔伊和罗斯吗
Phoebe, you picked Joey and Ross?
-你不能有两个备胎  -有何不可
- You can't have two backups! - Of course l can.
聪明人才会为备胎找备胎
lt's good sense to back up your backup.
-我已经折损钱德勒了  -什么
- Look, l've already lost Chandler. - What?
菲比  我们都是你的备胎吗
Hey, Phoebe! We're both your backup?
菲比  你怎么可以这样
Pheobe, How could you do this to me?
你们在抱怨什么啊  你们早就知道了
Why are you complaining? You were both aware of the situation.
-我不知道  -我们不知道
- l was not! - No, we weren't!
婚后你们可不能这样顶嘴
This kind of backtalk won't fly when we're married.
菲比  你不能独占他们  选一个
Phoebe you can’t have both of them! You have to pick one!
-选我  -不  选我
- Pick me! - No, pick me!
我不想当老处女
l don't wanna end up an old maid.
好吧  我看看
All right. Well, let's see.
罗斯是个好爸爸
Ross is a good father.
但是
But...
乔伊有船  好难选喔
...Joey has a boat. This is hard.
太扯了  我要换成瑞秋
This is crazy. Hey, look l wanna switch to Rachel.
-我也要换成瑞秋  -不  等一下
- l wanna switch to Rachel too. - No, wait. OK. Just wait.
你们别急着做决定
Wait, guys. Don't make any rash decisions.
记得我的承诺吧
Just remember my promise:
结婚之后  一星期三次
lf we get married, three times a week.
天哪  菲比
Oh, my God. Phoebe....
我是说按摩
l'm talking about massages.
不  我才不是
No, l'm not.
我知道该怎么解决了  办法就是
You know what, l know how to settle it. Alright. Here. We'll do this.
我在一张纸巾上写乔伊
l'm gonna write ''Joey'' on one napkin...
一张纸巾上写罗斯
...and I'm going to write ''Ross'' on the other napkin
一人选一张
and we're going to pick one.
选中的就是各自的备胎  好吗
And that person will be our backup. Okay?
-很公平  -行啊
- Sounds fair. - All right.
那好  我来弄乱
Good. Switching them up.
-选一边  -左边
- Pick one. - Left.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
-罗斯  -乔伊
- Ross. - Joey.
-我们交换好了  -没错
- We should switch. - Absolutely.
我想念这间房子  这才是大人的房子
l missed this apartment. Now, this is a grownup's apartment.
我应该跟大人在一起  你懂吧
l should be with a grownup, you know what I mean?
懂  你想要跟成熟的人在一起
Yeah. You're saying you need to be with someone more mature.
也许是一个
Maybe someone with...
有医师执照的人
...a license to practice medicine.
或是有胡子的人
Or a mustache.
说真的  我不是小孩子了
Let's face it. l'm not a kid anymore.
我需要一个目标相同的人
l need to be with someone who wants the same things that I do.
来我公司跟我示爱  我喜欢
Coming to my work and telling me you love me, l want that!
吃饭时聊猪的性爱  我不要那样
Talking about pig sex over lunch, l don't want that!
很公平
l think that's fair.
公平   别跟我提公平
Please, don't even talk to me about fair.
公平是你当年想娶我
Fair would've been you wanting to marry me back then.
或是钱德勒现在想娶我
Or fair would’ve been Chandler wanting to marry me now!
这整件事一点也不公平
Believe me, nothing about this is fair. Nothing.
-不公平不公平不公平...  -别激动
- Nothing! Nothing! Nothing! Nothing! Nothing!- lt's okay.
不公平
Nothing.
我不...我不知道
l don't know.
我不知道
我知道
l know.
我得先把事情想清楚
l have to figure some...
然后才能...
Some stuff, before l can....
我懂
l understand.
你只管慢慢想
Take as much time as you want.
十分钟  二十分钟都行
Ten, even 20 minutes, if you need it.
我会在这里  不会抽烟
l'll be here. Not smoking.
-钱德勒  -她人呢
- Chandler. - Where is she?
我可不怕你
l'm not scared of you.
她不在  请进
She's not here. And please come in.
威士忌加冰
Scotch on the rocks...
和莱姆片  放在杯垫上
...with a twist, on a coaster.
莫妮卡  莫妮卡
Monica? Monica?
好吧  她来过  又走了
Okay, she was here. But she left.
她去哪里
Where did she go?
她说她要想清楚
She said she had to think things over.
天哪  我真不敢相信
Oh, my God. l can't believe this. You know.
我以为...我以为你是个好人
l thought you were a good guy.
我们又没怎样
Look, nothing happened.
没怎样  没怎样
Nothing? Nothing happened?
你没跟我女朋友示爱吗
So you didn't tell my girlfriend you love her?
好吧  只有这样
Well, all right, one thing happened.
我真不敢相信
Y'know what? I can't believe this!
你知道你做了什么吗
Do you know what you did?
你让我女朋友重新思考
My girlfriend is thinking things over.
你让我的女朋友仔细考虑
You made my girlfriend think!
我很抱歉
Well, l'm sorry.
-她还需要想什么  -我爱她
- What's to think about? l love her.
但我愿意给她你不能给她的事情
Well, apparently I'm willing to offer her things that you were not.
我愿意给啊
But I am willing to offer her all those things.
我只是故意要让她失望
This was just a plan, y'know?
等真相大白
A way to throw her off course
她就会很惊喜万分
so that when I offered her all these things, she'd be surprised!
那你做的效果真的很好
If it helps, it worked very well.
谁让你半路杀出来了  程咬金
lt was working till you showed up, you big tree.
这样不公平
This isn't fair.
你曾经有机会  结果你搞砸了
You had your chance with her! You had your chance and you blew it!
现在轮到我了  我不会搞砸
And this is my chance and I am not going to blow it
因为我们是天生一对
because we are meant for each other.
而这一切只是个愚蠢的错误
And this has all just been one stupid mistake!
我本来打算今晚求婚的
l was gonna propose tonight.
-你要求婚啊  -对  我还...
- You were gonna propose? - Yeah, l even...
准备了戒指  你有吗
...got a ring. Did you get a ring?
没有  我没准备
No, l don't have a ring.
你去娶她吧  钱德勒
You go get her, Chandler.
我可以给你一个忠告吗
And can l give you a piece of advice?
要是你真娶到了她
lf you do get her...
一定要好好把握
...don't let her go.
相信我
Trust me.
理查德...你的确是个好人
You know, Richard, you are a good guy.
我知道
l know.
真讨厌
l hate that.
-待会再说  我得去找莫妮卡  -她走了
- l've gotta find Monica. - She's gone.
-什么  -她走了  提着一个包包走了
- What? - She's gone. She had a bag and she left.
-你在说什么  -她哭得很伤心
- What are you talking about? - She was all crying....
说你们要的东西不一样
She said you guys want different things.
说她需要时间思考
And she needed time.
你为什么不拦住她
Well why didn’t you stop her?!
告诉她我的计划
Why didn't you just tell her it was a plan?!
我有啊  我都说了
I-I did! I told her everything, Chandler!
但是她不信
But she wouldn't believe me.
那她...她上哪去了
Well, where...? Where did she go?
她父母家  她叫你不要打给她
To her parents' . She said you shouldn't call.
要是我就会打
But if l were you, l would.
-我居然搞砸了  -我很遗撼
- l can't believe l ruined this. - l am so sorry, man.
你希望是个惊喜的
You wanted it to be a surprise.
天哪
Oh, my God.
钱德勒...
Chandler...
我这辈子...
...in all my life...
从来没想过我会这么幸运
...l never thought l would be so lucky...
可以爱上我最要好的
...as to fall in love with my best....
我最要好的...
My best....
-所以说都是男人求婚嘛  -好好好
- There's a reason why girls don't do this! - OK. OK. OK.
我来  我以为
l'll do it. l thought....
等等  我一定行
Wait, l can do this.
我以为
l thought that it mattered...
开口的时间地点很重要
...what l said or where l said it.
后来才发现
Then l realized...
唯一重要的是你
the only thing that matters is that you....
你让我得到超乎想像的幸福
You make me happier than l ever thought l could be.
所以如果你愿意
And if you let me...
我愿意用下半生  让你跟我一样幸福
l'll spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way.
莫妮卡...
Monica...
你愿意嫁给我吗
will you marry me?
我愿意
Yes.
我就知道你应该会娶妻
l knew you were likely to take a wife!
可以进去了吗  我们快憋死了
Can we come in yet? We're dying out here!
进来  进来
Come in! Come in!
我们订婚了
We're engaged!
这是我最不嫉妒的时候
This is the least jealous l've ever been.
等等  不行啦  罗斯不在
Oh, no, wait! This is wrong! Ross isn't here!
他都玩三次了  知道是怎么回事
Hell, he's done it three times. He knows what it's about!